hey hey all right guys welcome to
another episode of the wasabi research
club today we are talking about zero
link the big point of fungibility
framework the the paper is available on
github the link is right here and it's
in on it's a work in progress it's
ongoing but it the the is mostly
formalized in 2017 don't say that and
this is what we've been doing so far so
if you recall the the last few weeks and
as always we will decide on the next
week's topic by the end of this wasabi
research Club meeting and of course you
can find out everything on via github at
the link below so we'll talk about the
fungibility and coin joints just go over
the basics of the zero like architecture
zero leak has many parts to it we're
going to focus on how the coordinator
can build a a coin joint without
requiring that the users trust the
coordinator we'll talk briefly about
attack vectors to zero link of mentions
in the article and I think just one that
I that I'll bring up and I'll just sort
of open it up and you know we're very
lucky in this in this call that we
happen to have one of the authors of a
paper on the call but for the life of me
I can't pronounce his name and I would
hate to be rude so we'll just leave that
out for now and just move forward
okay so we're familiar with the privacy
problem with Bitcoin transactions are
public inputs point imprimis on spent
outputs and then there's this whole
graph that's that's leaking sort of what
transactions are connected to other
transactions we've talked about before
the idea that if you have two users that
are engaging in transactions they can
join their transactions together so on
the Left we have two transactions
we have those two transactions joined
together just like this and we've talked
in the past about why you can't just do
this in a sort of simple way because
what happens to this you can sort of do
the math try to find the songs on the
left and it songs on the right and see
if you get a match so in this case you
know we can try to figure out a match of
57 and 15 there's no match there and so
you find another input and output until
you have a perfect match and then you
can quite easily take there's one
transaction break it back down into its
parts so it's not very safe to just take
any two transactions and combine them
together we've talked about equal
awkward acquaints so the idea here is
that you have these two individuals they
agree on some output in this case the
equal output is 10 they agree that they
will both create one anonymous output of
10 and when you combine these two
transactions together into one well what
happens is that even if you know the two
inputs are different people and you mark
them as different individuals you can
easily trace the change but you're left
with this question what about these two
outputs here you don't know where the
outputs belong to because they could
easily both belong to orange or yellow
equally there's no there's no special
hint as to whether these two outlets
belong to yellow or orange so the
question is how can this be coordinated
without loss of privacy so if we want to
make this this is a coin joint happen
we needed to be coordinated because
clearly two individuals working in
tandem that's some that requires
coordination so how are we going to do
this an option one is without a
coordinator we talked at length at
multiple meetings we talked about cash
fusion cash shuffle coin shuffle shuffle
plus plus talking about different ways
to get individuals to completely in a
decentralized way establish this
coordination but we the zero link paper
mentions this there
this is very tedious and cumbersome and
hard to improve hard to upgrade and so
it will be more ideal is a coordinator
that we don't trust obviously option TQ
is you know why don't we just use a
coordinator that we do trust you know
for example we could just have a single
essential server
everyone just sends the extended public
key to that server and the server will
will do the magic
and we hope the server doesn't reveal
that sensitive information to any other
individuals now that obviously sounds
pretty stupid so we're not going to do
that so what we're going to do is talk
about zero link coin joints or sometimes
called Tommy and blind coin joints or
more technically snoring blind coins
because we're using snore blind
signatures in the model so zero a coin
join chummy and blind or enjoin we'll
take these three users and as it turns
out I have a better presentation that I
did in the past which I'm going to
quickly pull up to explain this in part
because it's also copied from what David
made so we'll just use this here we go
so the the coordinator here is
interacting with a zero link wallet a
set of zero League wallets and the goal
is to build this final enjoyed
transaction right but we also want to
make sure that the wallets don't reveal
to the coordinator at a minimum the the
output that is anonymous because
otherwise it's not really anonymous so
this is broken down into phases phase
one Alice will a presented coin that
meets the minimum requirement for the
denomination that the coin joint is
doing so Alice will present the coin
Alice will also present truth of the
coin this proof is a signature with the
public key of where the coin is
currently stored Alice will also present
an output for the change because if we
are talking about a equal outward
join most almost all participants will
have change and that change is linkable
so the output is unblinded and Alice
will provide a blinded output for the
next coin this blinded output is
essentially in a dressed in a black
envelope that will be given to the
coordinator just not thing that a
coordinator will sign that black
envelope and the signature from the
coordinator will sleep through to the
paper inside the envelope and later
Alice can present it so the idea here is
that Alice is not giving up her address
instead she's hiding the address and
still getting a valid signature from the
coordinator so so the coordinator is
going to make sure that the input is in
fact confirmed and unspent but the
signature is valid that the that the
amount is correct and it'll the
coordinator will provide a signature for
the blinded output and Alice will store
that and that stays one so all the
participants are going to be essentially
registering in this stays one this is
the phase one is the longest base and it
will last for up to two hours
hypothetically it'd be classed as long
as you want in Phase two the connection
of all business will be confirms anyone
who is unconfirmed that means that would
have to be registered because otherwise
we don't know which I'm blind oh no
excuse me whoever is not confirmed that
coin will not be will not have to wait
for its signature because that user has
dropped out from connectivity and then
Albert registration and in this miss
phase all the users are going to
anonymously post overt or their outputs
that have invalid signature but are now
unblinded and this will allow the
coordinator to put all the outputs of
equal denomination on the right-hand
side of the quadrant transaction without
knowing who it is that because
who exactly presented that output it's
important that this algorithms roughly
at the same time so that all users are
sending their unblinded outputs over
toward at the same time so there's no
timing analysis by the coordinator or
anyone else and now that the coordinator
has this transaction which has all the
inputs it has all the anonymous outputs
and the change outputs now the
coordinator can present this unsigned
transaction to all the participants and
we reach the final stage which is the
signing stage of course if we did this
over the the clear Nets we would have an
issue where the coordinator would know
the location the IP address of all being
visuals or a passive bystander could
could sort of figure out who is
ascending outputs based on common IP
addresses and that's why everything has
to be done over a tour so all the
outputs inputs status requests all that
must be done over tor and support as
well that Newt or circus need to be
established for various parts of the
protocol so that again connecting the
particular inputs to outputs can't be
done okay so one of all the participants
get the final point they'll make sure
that they are not being cheated that we
have their output and their change and
then they'll present their signature and
give that back to the coordinator for
collection then what you point the
coordinator will be able to take a fully
signed transaction and broadcast in the
network all right so that is all that we
need for that part and we'll move on
right back
okay so the result is that we hit this
we have our participants they have a
equal valid coin joint we don't know who
which outputs belongs to whom although
the change is perfectly linked almost
every time if some in some instances
that the chain isn't perfectly linked
but in almost every instance the change
is what's one perfectly late and we
describe the level of anonymity of these
three outputs as in the same way that we
described tor anonymity which is to say
that it's as as anonymous as the other
participants in that are participating
in the coin joint so in this case we
would say the anonymity set is 3 but
that is just the theoretical upper bound
for the anonymity it could be much less
if someone gets compromised some
immediate limitations that you should
observe when we talk about zero link is
that mixing and sending are separated so
users will have to receive coins mix
those coins and then send those coins
and the mixing and sending are separated
a user may get many many outputs
depending on the amount of coins they
have which again is not ideal for a lot
of users if a user has a very large
amount of Bitcoin or a very very small
amount of Bitcoin they might be able to
they might not be able to participate or
they will participate and have many many
coins or just cumbersome nearly all
users will have some unmix change so if
we have a fixed amount almost everyone's
gonna have some change and that change
there's not anything that you can really
do with that change apart from you know
donate it open a lightning channel or
wait for more coins to come in so that
you can mix it with them and then users
really depend on the frequency and
behavior of other users so if you want
to mix very often and hopeful that many
people with the same denomination also
want to mix very often and of course
this model may had a lot of blow to the
network because we're doing a lot of
transactions where we're not sending
money to anyone we're just mixing money
so we're gonna briefly talk about
attackers and then
two questions so privacy is teamwork
what that means is that you are as
protected as the number of participants
that are behaving in an anonymous way as
you are if other participants fail to
act in a way that preserves their own
anonymity your anonymity has occurred
just by the fact that they have revealed
themselves this is a pretty obvious
concern so for example if orange is
revealed
now blue and yellow both have a reduced
anonymity and if blue is also revealed
than yellow without even knowing it you
know yellow could be doing everything
correctly but orange and blue failed to
act in an anonymous way they revealed
their their address links so now yellow
is by by elimination also revealed so
our attack vectors the first attacker
described in the beginning of repro that
the paper is a Doss attack now the idea
of a Doss attack is to stop the
coordinator from successfully making
more joints happen and the way this
attack of word is you have someone like
orange in this case who is purposefully
registering coins that are valid but
orange is going to purposefully not sign
transactions or do his or her best to
prevent the next coin dealer from
happening so maybe orange will take many
many many coins and continue to register
them and then purposefully not sign them
or maybe spend them before the core joy
is complete a few ideas were proposed in
the in the paper one is banning an IP
address which obviously wouldn't work
because we don't want to know the IP
address of a lot of the users so it's
going to be very hard to find out where
they are and we wouldn't want to use
that another way of dealing with this is
by completing the coin joint with a
subset so if a hundred participants have
joint and five are committing a dose tag
simply ban them
to continue with the 95 our meeting
participants and if you find another
three in there that are committing a
Doss attack purposefully not signing
then you banned them and you continue to
reduce the the number of people until
you have only the people that are
legitimate this is also not not ideal
but it's it's it doesn't work at least
although it's not it's you know it's not
perfect so there's also they do have
closed-source das protection so maybe
you know you could have everything open
sourced but the das protection you might
have a closed source so that it's harder
for an attacker to establish the optimal
way to attack you and the attacker has
to sort of a reverse engineer your your
prevention a pretty interesting idea
about but I believe by Chris Belcher is
the use of fidelity bonds essentially
bitcoin that you put in escrow that you
will lose if you fail to engage in a
protocol this is quite a cumbersome it
demands that the the round take a lot
longer and has been sort of opposed by
quite a few individuals and lastly we
have banning the registration of
provided utx o--'s and related new taxes
of malicious alice and this is quite
simple so if the particular coin didn't
assign simply bad that coin and been its
children and its parents potentially it
you know for let's say an hour and then
if the attack persists for a while you
can ban for longer periods of time like
a day or a week obviously the concern
here is that people will refuse banning
refuse signing by accident if the tor
circuit breaks if the internet
connection goes down whatever maybe you
don't want to have someone stranded with
unlink waits for a week because you
wrongfully assume that they're trying to
commit a daus attack so this one
obviously works but it's a bit of a
double-edged sword we have to be careful
amour another attack which is kind of
interesting in its own right is the
simple attack
now the civil attack comes from an
individual who purposefully does engage
with it or join and does go through and
the entire Corps join but the ideas of
the individual has presented many many
many inputs that they alone hold and
what they're trying to do is they try to
eliminate the potential outputs of other
participants by excluding their own
inputs so let's say instead of three
participants we actually have two
participants one is green who is
malicious and yellow who is honest and
green here has green change outputs and
green mixed outputs and as you can see
green alone can see that the third
output is the only other output that
doesn't belong to them so they can
quickly narrow down the anonymity set in
this case down to one but it doesn't
necessarily have to be down to one it
could just be severely reduced and the
last one we'll talk about before we just
open up the condoms of questions because
I'm sure that people have a lot of
things to say is that behavior
discrepancy is a big one so just like in
tour we talked about how in tour the
problem is is that if there aren't
enough users that behave the way you
behave then you're singled out so for
example if the user arrives with an
amount of Bitcoin far larger than the
users in the pool they will be detected
if they read combined coins post mix
we've seen a lot of people in the public
square a lot of thing and poking about
this the fact that you know whales come
in two to a zero link protocol and when
they exit it's obvious and therefore the
system doesn't work it's more fair to
say that the system does not work for
people who are acting alone if you have
ten thousand Bitcoin and everyone else
has a you know between one and ten
Bitcoin and you enter with ten thousand
and leave with ten thousand yes you are
much much easier to spot another thing
we might see is that if the user sends
funds and coin joins during an uncommon
time zone they could also be detected so
timing analysis based on when people
makes an
that is another big issue and lastly we
talked a bit about the philosophy of
building privacy systems in anonymity
networks and how the way that user puts
the settings on their wallets can reveal
themselves as being unique if they said
the settings in a very particular way
they can actually hurt themselves and
this is things like for example setting
a custom fee when you send funds or when
you send funds how often how frequently
and so forth
so concluding thoughts zero link is a
sponge ability protocol based on an
untrusted central coordinator equal
output mixing and the anonymity of large
crowds much like tor it is a system a
pledge ability based on anonymity
networks so I want to leave it at that
but I will say there's a lot of things I
want to say and could say you know about
for example current implementations or
what I think you know how wasabi works
in practice or other attack vectors but
I think that will sort of uncover them
together as a group as we talk further
on and I'll bring them up if no one
brings them up and that's pretty much it
for me okay thank you for the ironic or
an ironic clapping I'm not sure which
one knows good question about the simple
attacks has that ever been something
that wasabi or anyone in the community
has detected occurring I know it was a
very large consideration in the original
work no I think it's not possible it's
if you think it through
I mean okay how would you define CBL is
easy BL the anonymization of an output
complete the anonymization of an output
or or it's okay if you if you take like
50% of the mix and then they gain half
as much unanimity than they want what
but we'd never say for the studio
yeah I probably need to be deionization
to the point that you can narrow it down
to suspects for example if it was used
in some sort of criminal investigation
because I imagine nation-states are the
only ones who have the kind of funds to
conduct a civil attack it's expensive
100 you need to provide 99 peers for
every single coin that that wants to do
coin join and I there is oh actually now
I I can count with that because I know
the exact number
you know this fresh Bitcoin thing the
wasabi Co enjoying efficiency github
repository I created that I I look at
how much fresh Bitcoin comes into Vasavi
daily and for that you have to provide
99 times as much in order to completely
do anonymize every single wasabi mixes
and there is 500 fresh Bitcoin coming
into wasabi daily which would mean you
would have to provide 99 times 500
Bitcoin to disability' cassabi that's
the that's the number there we need the
more likely scenario be a simple attack
targeting an individual output rather
than all the Saudi users but you cannot
target like that you will have to
get all the subuser actually the
coordinator could selectively target
right that that is that is possible yeah
yeah well but wanting to consider
principal attacks instead against anyone
other than the civil attacker you still
get a minute he said of course depending
on pre and post makes coin behavior but
but if for example one one guy has 99
outputs and for an outside observer it's
doable 100 an anime teaser I mean I
didn't think of it but now that you
bring it up if you select one input
exactly or or then then you can provide
the coordinator is the only one who can
who can make sure that which inputs are
participating right that's that's the
dose protection there so so yeah it's if
the coordinator has 99 times as much
coins actually not even 99 times because
because it has to because it can lower
the day on all set although if you lower
down on set for 4 - that's not workable
because then the guy is going to mix his
coin like like like like 50 times in
order to get the get the green shield so
so yeah at 50 times now not 99 times 50
times as much as much as you want to do
the anonymize someone it's actually yeah
I I did not think about it now it seems
Moria and just I'm just catching this
one on the fly that
yeah the coordinator should be able to
to severe attack
but what anything as his is completely
unrealistic there that's really the 99
times 500 Bitcoin daily that's how much
has to be lattaker would need he cannot
he cannot even decide which machine
could city's attacking you know so it's
a matter of liquidity rather than
expense in the case the coordinators the
attacker because the coordinator
receives the fee for the coin joint as
well
yeah I didn't even talk about fees I was
only talking about the initial initial
requirements the individual requirements
at this point yes the coordinator would
have to pay Network fist - yeah it's
that that's not that difficulty there
sure
anyway guys I'm not bringing up topics
here because that that would be strange
so I guess we can we can finish this
this up or or or do you guys have
something no I definitely have quite a
lot of stuff I think we can talk about
so unless what are we gonna talk about
after after this Adam did you have
something to talk about after this okay
so I feel like this is somewhat an
outdated paper other than the Jamie and
Coen Jane stuff
nothing aged that well other than the
basic decor protocol nothing aged that
like the zero link framework was was not
a very successful in inside this wasn't
successful because this was supposed to
be used by multiple wallets that's why
so much time was spent on making sure
the bullets aren't around finger
printable but but as as time went on it
became more and more clear that that
cannot be made sure and it's not like
many wallets would have been interested
in privacy so so I think that was kind
of a waste of time and a waste of space
on github to to specify so so many
things there the coins are in protocol
the Charmian Cohen jury in protocol
actually aged very well and that's other
than implementation details everything
is the same
if there were guys here link library
would that make a difference if from
wasabi wallet there was an engine that
just powered zero link that one could
build a wallet on top of not sure but I
wouldn't bother with it because we are
working on how would you say it's zero
link 2.0 but it's not even 2.0 it it's a
it's a similar thing it solves the
issues that that the chummy and
conjoined think has like oh there is a
minimal denomination or you cannot send
in the coin join so it solves the the
largest issues there and and and I
wouldn't bother with which they don't
link anymore because this this thing is
it's going to happen going to be be
released in in in this year I'm keep
referring to this distinct because we
don't have a name yet
and we just started it today but it was
an extremely promising day so I'm really
excited about this guys Marx wrote in in
the chat that he has a very shitty
connection so he wrote a couple of
messages with questions to the chat the
first is how does the new implementation
of mixing with multiple woman in one
instance affect Sibyl attacks anyone
wants to winstram that okay loud and
clear the second question was what is
the current implementation of dust
protection in wasabi how did you call it
just white bedding coins yeah
burning coins so if someone doesn't sign
it is banned right now for two hours
because it's we don't really have denial
of service attacks it's more like
unreliable anonymity Network unreliable
tor connection that seems like much more
of an issue than than we thought and of
course honest peers cannot be
differentiated malicious peers cannot be
differentiated from peers those has bad
connections or or or not even not even
individual connections but but the
connection can be bad through the onion
Network the route that you choose so so
that's that that's a huge protect
practical issue there and and yeah it's
it's it's it's it's bending Cohen's from
participating for for some time we are
also going up and down on the
transaction chain so for example if you
spend that coin then you still cannot
register into to the wasabi mix because
well that would be going around the dose
protection although this this gets
expensive for that occur anyway it's it
just banning Cohen's it doesn't I would
love if someone put this to the test but
because we didn't even had to use our
very basic configurations and we
actually wrote a lot of code to to be
able to even make this much more severe
so if someone would attack wasabi and
would be successful then we could just
change one line in the configuration and
and and he would have to come up with a
completely new strategy so I feel very
confident about that at this point and
and I I don't know I no one bothers to
to attack it but maybe it's because
because if hacker hackers don't want to
attack it because there is nothing to
gain from it
generally these companies don't want to
attack it because it's illegal so that
that could hit her isn't there okay
perfect
another question no I don't can you
speak more about your coin joints to
docq analysis of change outputs did I
wrote anything about this thing zero
link yeah I'm not sure I'm just reading
what max sent me III sorry max can you I
don't know what max has it max has a
very bad connection now so he's just
sending over his questions in chats and
I just read in them out loud basically
so yeah that was his question about your
core joint sort of analysis of change
outputs
deinonychus he says that you did
analysis of change with coin join Sudoku
and the non equal value outputs created
yeah I got the information I had is aut
EXO that was smaller than the the D
denomination the base denomination and I
give it to try to the anonymous it
and I couldn't that's that's pretty much
it even though I know other coins must
had been meshed together in the mix
there were more possibilities than then
I I initially thought so I couldn't
figure out which even which which coins
it joined that coin together read so so
yeah it was a interesting exercise I
hope that would answer this question I
just have one more question about the
max Max's first question about the
multiple wallets in one instance doesn't
it just make a Sybil attack a little bit
easier that the attacker doesn't have to
run
like many wasabi bullets she could just
read so yes it does make it a little bit
easier but if someone really wants a
simple attack and they want a simple
attack wasabi specifically they're gonna
need hundreds of thousands of dollars
worth of Bitcoin and they're gonna need
to be quite dedicated so or is it if
they if they can get hundreds of
thousands of dollars of Bitcoin and they
have a committed attitude to breaking
this they probably know how to do it
with or without multi wallet support
they probably are comfortable running it
on multiple subsystems that would only
add a little bit of cost compared to the
cost of the Bitcoin they would have to
have to do it so I don't think so but
what it does do is it does mitigate the
person who has maybe two businesses or
one business and a personal account and
they don't want to reveal to the world
that those two things are related and if
they try to manage it in one wallet they
can accidentally cue coins together and
do all sorts of things whereas if they
now have two separate wallets which they
can link in
at the same time and coin join at the
same time then it will be easier to
protect them yeah definitely and I do
agree I mean I don't see Sybil attack as
a actual like real risk in Wasabi's case
I think there's much better things for
these companies to do if they would try
to do something so yeah so let's talk
about that a bit right so how so with a
civil attack you want to have as many
helpless as possible that you know and
that that allows you to narrow down the
of the other outputs you know if there
are even two honest participants then
you can reduce the anonymity set all the
way down to two one thing to note is
that if two people are engaging in a
civil attack at the same time but
they're not coordinating with each other
then they further add anonymity so the
the simple attacker is in a quite a
difficult spot because they have to hope
that there aren't a lot of people
participating the only one engaging in
this attack so I I think it is quite
unreasonable however if you drunk the
anonymity said about have a coin joint
down to you let's say I don't know I'll
top my head let's say five which would
be a really bad idea
but I don't know let's just off top my
head then it is very practical to do
with this attack right and I talked
about this at length how you would do it
if there was if the upper limit of a
courtroom was five participants all you
would be five or even ten large coins
put the one on separate computers or
separate you know instances of your your
your coin joint
software and you just hope that enough
collisions of your ten instances appear
on on any given point and if you have
will give you one collision like that is
to say two of your your your wallets
intersect it
yeah I totally agree with that I mean it
has to have enough participants per
round to be actually effective against
the civil attack and also to have a big
enough of amount except minimal but we
thought the round okay so if no one else
doesn't mean you say I want to bring up
another thing so let's let's talk about
the unanimity set a bit right so in my
presentation I talked about coin joints
as though they happen in a vacuum
there's just one coin joint but we all
know that Cohen joints happen
sequentially and most participants will
engage in more than one coin joint
because they have more than one clean
coin that they can receive so you know
if you look at a core joint in a vacuum
the anonymity sets pretty obvious it's
the number of honest participants in
that coin joint and we assume because we
could possible to prove otherwise we
assume that the theoretical limit is
that everyone is honest now if a person
remixes and suppose they remix in the
adjacent coin joint
they're gonna obviously get some
additional benefit and I think this is
where Adam and I have have had
disagreements at times which is that I
don't believe that remakes thing in an
adjacent go in joint does even it does
as much as even double the anonymity set
that you currently have so if there's 50
participants in the first and then 50
participants in the second the likely
unanimity set of engaging in both those
coin joints with the remix is probably
you know from 50 to 60 or from 50 to 70
and and the absolute upper bound would
100 but it's unlikely because other
participants also engage in sequential
coin joints so you're hiding in the same
crowd of people and I'm curious if
anyone has a on that well I do agree
that it's kind of like the more accurate
way to just say it would be like the for
example for one remix round your total
anonymity set as a like a maximum could
be like the amount of UT exo's in the
second mix - the ones that came from the
previous mix from the previous round and
also like adding all the persons or the
participants who were in the first round
I mean some kind of mix from those and
yeah I kind of understand your point
that it's not like they're 200 think
about it in a probability from
probability point of view rather than
unanimity set point of view if you mix
take take a coin take your coin take a
round on coin from the blockchain and
mix that now you're going to get a zero
point one Bitcoin out of of that mix and
of well the zero point one Bitcoin
output half of them are remixed and
another half of them are not remixed so
there is a 50% chance that you remix
that random coin but you just took from
the beginning and on the next go
enjoying again a 50% chance that it's
gonna be remixed and on the next coin
join again a 50% chance if it's going to
be remixed
and now work with these probabilities so
what are the chances that you are going
to remix three times and that's not much
that's that's very mixing that's why
people talk about the exponential
privacy gains of free mixing still not
sold in particular so it it comes down
to the actual user behavior of the
propensity of someone to remix so before
you know you know in theory any coin in
any mixed coin from wasabi could be a
coin from two years ago that's just been
remix thing and remixing and re mixing
well however what's more likely is that
you know that there's a 50% chance that
it from a direct participant a brand new
another 50% is that it makes when you
say remix we mostly mean in the sorry
you actually got it yourself next here
we go so I really don't don't buy this
because and I've had this argument with
another some other folks about about
this matter but of those remixers most
are coming from the previous conjoint of
which half of them are new mixers and so
when you do this when you go back you
know to say 2 or 3 or 4 remixes you're
already getting to a very very
infinitesimally small probability and
the majority are from you know let's say
4 coin joints of which most of those
people have inter as
overlap of participants so again you
have a very you know potentially a
linear climb in terms of anonymity but
the only way I would I would be I would
say I'm wrong is is it the nature of
wasabi was such that people who mixed
older coins had a priority in remixing
such that coins from very distant coin
joints had an advantage to participate
in new coin joints and then I would say
there's more probably it's still
probably linear but it's at least faster
in terms of the anonymity said growth
may I just add one more question about
that I mean let's just think about like
two rounds of mixing the first one you
have hundreds of participants you are
one of those let's say that 50 of them
goes and remixes on the second round and
there's also like 100 participants
wouldn't your anonymity set be like from
the first round you would get like 100
from the outsiders I'm unsure from which
perspective to look at this but I mean
you could get like anonymity set of 50
from the first round and if there is no
remixes after the second round wouldn't
it be like more of likes 150 more than
closer than the 200 and it shows
correctly it would be 150 you're exactly
right except it would be a hundred and
fifty with a caveat which and the caveat
is the probability so there's a 50%
chance it's it's one of the 50 people
right and then there's a 50% chance it's
one of the hundred so in other words if
you say is it is it someone from the
first coin joined the answer is there's
like a like there's a smaller
probability it's from the first coin
join than it is from the second coin
join in terms of the participation so
it's not a uniform probability but
you're right it's a hundred and fifty
anonymity set and not not 200 also it's
very important understand
that it displays how inefficient it is
to have small coin joints the bigger the
conjoined the much much more efficient
yes I had a question that if if the
current implementation is vulnerable to
Wagner attack for those of you don't
know Wagner attack is this is possible
in V dash nor blinding signature scheme
and it it works something like this you
you get more and more signatures the
more likely that you can you can I don't
know what you can do with that but the
more likely that you can execute this
Wagner's attack I don't remember exactly
what happened but but that's something
that we consider affect them and so so
you need more signatures from blind
signatures from the same pop key and you
also need more time and that's how we we
mitigated it first we don't give out
that many signatures and you also don't
have time because we only give out the
signatures in the end of connection
confirmation phase so from from their
own you only have three minutes maybe
two to execute this attack so that's not
not not not very doable also very we
don't reuse the design in keys so every
round the new signing key is generated
that's the that's the that's that's
that's that was our mitigation there
yeah
okay thank you
this this is a question also that all
the posted previously why did we switch
from Charmian to snore blanching
signatures because we introduced the
denomination and there is another attack
if the coordinator lies about the the
deed around parameters and the most
important such transferometer is the
public keys so so we introduced the new
denominations and now every denomination
needs a new a new public a new new
signing key so the thing is that the the
RSA signature scheme is extremely heavy
and our mitigation of the coordinator
lying would be that that we are somewhat
probabilistically mitigating that there
is a monitoring identity in every client
not only those who participate but but
every one and every time and you keep
sending the the backend server a request
that a status request and that status
request returns a a a fair amount of
things like the filters that returns the
Bitcoin price that returns a couple of
things but it also returns the the
public keys of this round so it returns
11 public key and this is we did with
RSA scheme this this would be a huge
amount of network traffic but with
snowblind signatures this is just this
is just
256-byte I'm not quite sure but but it's
it's it's much smaller so we we begin
gain some some edge there that because
it's much smaller and it's a very
frequent request
imagine it like this every every minute
someone every minute your client sends a
request I'm not even sure if every
minute even more frequently maybe sends
a request to the back end that hey give
me your status and every time the
backend ants were sweet with the 11
public key of disco enjoy me round even
if you are not going joining so we had
to had to do to lower that also another
consideration was that we did not want
to rely on different cryptographic
assumptions because Bitcoin already
realized on a little curve cryptography
an and and so we we didn't have to rely
on their assay cryptography here
interesting okay I guess if nothing
nothing is there then then I want to to
go into the future bit more and just to
keep you guys up to date updated that
nothing much and east van Sheriff Ron
rash and me started working on the new
coins the new mixing scheme today and I
have to say it's much more it's even
more promising than I thought so nothing
much just outlined a few things that I
didn't think that was actually solvable
and we are only so we don't want to
leave you out we are only working on a
first draft which is about we don't we
take a lot of things out of the scope
even the network fees everything this is
only about to present the idea in a in a
very digestible way
so I was thinking we can do this in ER
in just just this week but as as I said
nothing much presented something that
could be much more that that could be
quite revolutionary to be honest and and
that's something that has to be explored
before the idea is presented and and
this is the anonymous what is it
anonymous crashes and there is a paper
which I would like to propose for the
next was a bee research Club anonymous
credentials paper and that way maybe we
could figure out if this this is
something that that could work or or or
not so that's that's that's about it I
am really excited actually that after
today and and and and and get you guys
as soon as we we finish just a quick
draft of the idea and share with you and
and everyone can can participate and
join and and whatever you guys would
would like to do with it if you would
and that would be great and work out the
research together perfect thanks for the
update Adam can I ask you to maybe it's
possible to shift its kind of recession
that you have to mainly research thread
and slack I mean that would be very
helpful because for example in RGB there
are a bunch of protocols that might be
useful for you also and I want to make
sure that there is or there is a synergy
that we can work on together or there is
no synergetic list yet and I can just
stay updated something like that I don't
think so
it's hard enough to to follow each one
and nothing much to be done and handed
em just the two of them and I I mean
there is a limited capacity of how much
information we can we can get in and if
if people keep coming with with new
things like oh let's put it to the
Lightning Network and pay to endpoint
and things like that so I I really want
to rule out as many things of the scope
of this first idea presentation as
possible and after that yes but but but
until we don't have a stable idea I I
would prefer not to so I I would kind of
prefer if a weave could participate I'm
not quite sure about because it's like
he has another job to do and I just you
know I'll do it you know I love my job I
always I would never okay I don't try
now really okay the anonymous crashes
paper maybe maybe maybe that will give
everyone the same idea what we are doing
I don't know you see if we stop
recording no not yet so don't say you're
quitting I'm stopping the recording all
right
greeting
[Music]